<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Purdue ARC – Purdue ARC</title><link>https://purduearc.com/</link><description>Recent content on Purdue ARC</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://purduearc.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: RISE</title><link>https://purduearc.com/blog/2023/03/16/rise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purduearc.com/blog/2023/03/16/rise/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;em>This page will continue to be updated with more info.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are thrilled to share the news of &lt;strong>RISE: The 1st Robotics and Intelligent Systems Expo&lt;/strong> by &lt;a href="https://www.purduearc.com/">ARC&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://engineering.purdue.edu/ICON">ICON&lt;/a>, planned to take place in Hampton Hall (Rooms 2113-8), Saturday, April 15th, 2023, from 11AM-4PM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is &lt;em>RISE&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A premier conference dedicated to exhibiting the newest innovations in robotics and intelligent systems.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A convergence of experts from Purdue research labs and student organizations to demonstrate their cutting-edge innovations and explore the future of these dynamic fields.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An endeavor to keep Purdue University at the forefront of the growing global focus on robotics and artificial intelligence.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Why Participate in &lt;em>RISE&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On behalf of your student organization:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>An exceptional platform for your members to demonstrate their work through posters, or oral presentations, and compete for awards, further elevating the visibility and recognition of your club and its projects.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A valuable opportunity to recruit talented students to your org.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>On behalf of your research lab:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A valuable opportunity to attract talented undergraduate and graduate students to join your lab or contribute to your area of research.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An exceptional platform to demonstrate your lab&amp;rsquo;s work through posters or presentations, and compete for awards, further elevating the visibility and recognition of your research lab.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If this conference sounds interesting to you, the official registration form is now open! Students (undergrad or grad), are encouraged to sign up on behalf of their project/organization by Monday, April 10th, using the form below. Spaces are limited, and will be offered on a first come, first serve basis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd5bpwo8BXstems2TyBOSIgnluge0ggDia_Ge_7gtt6_fGcIA/viewform?usp=sf_link">https://forms.gle/hGWQpb8aE5EoB9Bs5&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We look forward to seeing you there!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Fall 2022 Callout</title><link>https://purduearc.com/blog/2022/08/14/fall-2022-callout/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purduearc.com/blog/2022/08/14/fall-2022-callout/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Interested in joining ARC? Attend one of our Fall 2022 callout events during the second week of school.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will discuss the general organization of ARC, as well as some of our past projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The details for these callout events are as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tuesday, August 30th, from 6:00-7:00pm at ARMS B061&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thursday, September 1st, from 6:00-7:00pm at ARMS B061&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As you can see, they both take place in the basement of Armstrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Outside of attending the callout, you should join the discord (linked &lt;a href="https://purduearc.com/join">here&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>