<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Purdue ARC – Purdue ARC Blog</title><link>https://purduearc.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Purdue ARC Blog on Purdue ARC</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://purduearc.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: RobotCon Announcement</title><link>https://purduearc.com/blog/2023/02/16/robotcon-announcement/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purduearc.com/blog/2023/02/16/robotcon-announcement/</guid><description>
&lt;p>On behalf of ARC, I am thrilled to share the news of our upcoming inaugural event, RobotCon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is RobotCon?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A premier conference planned to take place in MSEE on April 7th, 2023, dedicated to exhibiting the newest innovations in robotics and autonomy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A convergence of experts from Purdue research labs, student organizations, and industry partners to demonstrate their cutting-edge innovations and explore the future of these dynamic fields.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An endeavor to keep Purdue University at the forefront of the growing global focus on robotics and artificial intelligence.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Why Participate in RobotCon?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a student club:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A valuable opportunity to recruit talented undergraduate and graduate students to your club.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An exceptional platform for your members to demonstrate their work through demos, posters, or oral presentations, and compete for awards, further elevating the visibility and recognition of your club and its projects.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As a research lab:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A valuable opportunity to attract talented undergraduate and graduate students to join your lab or contribute to your area of research.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An exceptional platform for your students to demonstrate their work through posters or oral presentations, and compete for awards, further elevating the visibility and recognition of your lab.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If this event sounds interesting to you, please take 2 minutes to answer the following Qualtrics survey by Tuesday, February 21st. This does not represent a final decision or a commitment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://purdue.ca1.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_08RogL7amwafaia">https://purdue.ca1.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_08RogL7amwafaia&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We look forward to seeing you at the event!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Fall 2022 Callout</title><link>https://purduearc.com/blog/2022/08/14/fall-2022-callout/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://purduearc.com/blog/2022/08/14/fall-2022-callout/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Interested in joining ARC? Attend one of our Fall 2022 callout events during the second week of school.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will discuss the general organization of ARC, as well as some of our past projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The details for these callout events are as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tuesday, August 30th, from 6:00-7:00pm at ARMS B061&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Thursday, September 1st, from 6:00-7:00pm at ARMS B061&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As you can see, they both take place in the basement of Armstrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Outside of attending the callout, you should join the discord (linked &lt;a href="https://purduearc.com/join">here&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>